{
    "id": "c72824fa753c4f77b91a7a84e5da82a0",
    "title": "Gerund vs. Infinitive",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We stopped ........................... a drink.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to have",
                "having",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He stopped .............................. when he developed liver trouble.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to drink",
                "drinking",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He started .................................. at thirteen.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to work",
                "working"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I stopped ............................... them at school.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "dropping",
                "to drop"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I remember ................................ him at the bus stop.",
            "description": "A gerund after remember refers to the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "to meet",
                "meeting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Remember ............................. the check before Friday.",
            "description": "An infinitive after remember refers to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "posting",
                "to post"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Did you remember ............................... the door when you left?",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "locking",
                "to lock"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I don't ever remember ................................. to her.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to talk",
                "talking"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I regret ............................. school at fifteen.",
            "description": "An infinitive after regret refers to the present or future. A gerund refers to the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to leave",
                "leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I regret ................................ you that you have lost your job.",
            "description": "An infinitive after regret refers to the present or future. A gerund refers to the past.",
            "answers": [
                "informing",
                "to inform"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would like ………………………………. this scenery.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used to talk about doing something on a specific occasion. The gerund is used for making general statements or to refer to things happened in the past.",
            "answers": [
                "painting",
                "to paint"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I like ………………………………",
            "description": "Either could be used here. However, generally speaking, the gerund is more appropriate here. ",
            "answers": [
                "to paint",
                "painting",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}